PHIL SAMBATI - CURRICULUM VITAE



△ Contact information

Full Name: **Phil Sambati** Address: Majadahonda, Spain Email:phil.sambati@gmail.com Phone number: +34 692 60 58 93

Website: <u>www.philsambati.com</u> LinkedIn profile: <u>LinkedIn</u>



Professional summary

As a Learning and Development specialist with 15+ years of experience, I specialize in digital transformation, learning strategy, and technology implementation to enhance organizational capability. I've led international projects with UNESCO, Nokia, and RMIT across Europe, Asia, and Africa, delivering strategic frameworks, blended learning solutions, and Al-driven initiatives. With a human-centred approach, I use technology to empower learning.



Experience



Role: Blended Learning Development Manager

Duties: I develop learning content and integrate AI into learning design to enhance engagement and effectiveness. I focus on leveraging AI for content localization, ensuring international technical materials are adapted to diverse audiences with precision and relevance

Dates: July 2024 – Present

Dates: Aug 2022—July 2024

Company: RMIT University SEUP

Role: Digital Learning Manager

Duties: I managed digital learning initiatives, seamlessly integrating curriculum, assessment, and professional development to support program goals. A key achievement was developing a comprehensive digital framework for the new curriculum, which laid the foundation for innovative blended course designs. By combining strategic planning with hands-on implementation, I ensured a cohesive approach to enhancing learning experiences across diverse programs.

Company: International Baccalaureate Dates: Jan 2019 - July 2022

Role: Senior Learning Designer

Duties: I collaborated with the curriculum team to design professional development training using instructional system design principles. I developed strategic models and innovative methods for learning delivery, and managed the learning management system and associated technologies to enhance educational outcomes.

PHIL SAMBATI - CURRICULUM VITAE

Company: International Livestock Research Institute **Dates**: Sept 2016 - Dec 2018

Role: Instructional Design Specialist

Duties: I designed and developed capacity-building interventions, overseeing the entire process from needs analysis to final evaluation. This comprehensive approach ensured impactful training and development across diverse areas.

Company: E-Learning consultant **Dates**: Jan 2015 – Sept 2015

Role: E-Learning and Development Consultancy

Duties: Managed the development of a digital platform including the technologies and pedagogies.

Company: British Council **Dates**: Jan 2011 - Jan 2015

Role: Digital Training Manager Sub-Saharan Africa

Duties: I managed self-access learning and digital portfolios, driving education technology projects across sub-Saharan Africa. My work focused on implementing innovative, sustainable solutions to improve learning access and outcomes in underserved and resource-limited environments.



Education

Institution: University of Edinburgh Napier Dates: 2011-2014

Qualification: MSc Blended and Online Master's in technology enhanced education, blended learning and online learning pedagogy and design.

▶ **Institution**: British Council Madrid **Dates**: 2005 - 2007

Qualification: Diploma English Language Teaching NVQ level 7 advanced professional Diploma in English language teaching.

👼 Certificates

- Certified Associate in Project Management (APMP/ PMQ) foundational project management certificate
- M&E Professional certificate in monitoring and evaluation theory and practice.
- CCNA/ MCSE Cisco networking associate, Microsoft server administration additional knowledge of Transact SQL and Exchange server.



Learning Theory and Instructional Design

 Curriculum development, instructional system design: SAM, ADDIE, 4C-ID, Backwards Design,

PHIL SAMBATI - CURRICULUM VITAE

- Learning theories: Experiential learning, Adult learning, Community of Inquiry framework, cognitive load theory, gamification, micro-learning. Multimedia principles
- Evaluation and analytics: Monitoring and evaluation, learning analytics, educational data mining

Technology and Design Skills

- E-learning development: Articulate, Evolve, Lectora, Moodle, Canvas, Docebo
- Instructional media: Vyond, Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, XD, Audition), Camtasia
- UI/UX Focus: IA/UX design, Design thinking
- Data tools: Power BI, Excel, Tableau

Project Management and Workflow

• Methodologies and project software: Agile, Kanban, waterfall, Jira, Smartsheet

Emerging Technology and Development

- Al: Prompt engineering, local and open source LLM usage (Langchain, Ollama), Al media (Whisper, Eleven labs, NotebookLM, Qwen, Veo), foundation model use (Claude, OpenAl, Gemini)
- Cloud and dev tools: Google Cloud Platform, Collab, PowerApps, AWS, Jupyter, Python
- Integrations and data: APIs (REST, xAPI, LTI, CMI5), Databases (SQL, Neo4J, Firebase),
 HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Projects and publications

RMIII	Al Data analytics	RMIT Media, Saigon Times
IBO	Micro learning courses	Micro learning PD
ILRI	Value Chain 360 video Publications	YouTube 360 video link IBLI e-learning, Africa Rising Capacity needs assessment and summary
British Council	Learn English Audio Projec	t <u>South Africa DBE link</u> , <u>LEAP Ethiopia</u> , <u>LEAP Nigeria</u>



Please visit my portfolio website if you want to find out more.